NETWORK ENGINEER 1

Summary

Highly motivated and goal driven IT Professional with experience and knowledge of various hardware, software, and operating systems. Detailed oriented with strong work ethic, problem-solving, quick learner and master new technology; equally successful in both team and self-directed settings Consistently recognized for exceptional troubleshooting skills used to rapidly resolve technical challenges in a timely manner and also recognized in providing exception world class customer service. Â Hard worker with a can do attitude âcego getterâc and a willingness to learn new technologies, customer service oriented and proactive.

Highlights

OS/Platforms: AS/400, MS Windows NT/9x/2000/XP Server 2003/2008 Dell, Apple and HP Workstations, ios Application/Tools: Microsoft Active Directory, Microsoft Office Suite (XP,2003

Experience

Network Engineer 1 Jul 2013 to Current

Apex Systems il/4 Falls Church, VA

- Provides technical support to both Windows and Linux servers infrastructure (80%VM/20%Phy).
- Monitors windows and network infrastructure ensuring proper documentation and regulatory compliance and all machines have the latest security updates and anti-virus updates.
- Develops standard images for desktops and laptops.•Configures IP phones and voice mail as necessary. Provides second level support to the service desk function.
- Installs OS and configures server for use in the field and data center.

IT Service Desk Analyst I Mar 2010 to Jul 2013

Consulate Health Care i1/4 Melbourne, FL

- Provide routine desktop/laptop support for the Houston Corporate office of over 250 users and remote support for over 150 field office in US and internationally Monitor and route service desk email inbox inquiries.
- Answer on average 25-30 service desk calls Provide iPad and iPhone support as well as blackberry.
- Provide Remote access for external consultants and dial in users Support Citrix clients and applications Create, close and update the various daily work tickets from Service Now Ticketing and document in a timely manner according to various SLA's.
- Set up network user accounts/permissions user groups and or distributions, reset passwords and Unlock AD accounts Administers enduser security provisioning, de-provisioning in various Key Energy Applications Work with hardware and software vendors to resolve issues and implement new products.
- Setup and configure cisco phones Analyze and make recommendations for hardware and software standardization Deploy hardware and software to the end users, including VOIP telephony.

Server Test Technician Jan 2010 to Mar 2010

Accenture i1/4 Jackson, MS

- Run QC Testing and diagnostics software on Servers.
- Install/replace internal server components such as Processor, hard drive, video card, motherboard, NIC cards, etc.
- Set up the servers to run tests for the CTO (configure to order) and BTO (build to order) server products.

PC System Builder/Quality Controller May 2009 to Aug 2009

Courseleaf i1/4 Coralville, IA

- Assembled, Build and Test Hardware for Custom Computer Systems for Local School Districts.
- Performed Quality Control test on computer Systems.
- Setup and Configured New Computer Systems for local Schools.

Desktop Support Intern Jun 2006 to Jul 2008

Baker Hughes i1/4 City, STATE

- Provided Seconded level Desktop support to Multinational Corporation troubleshoot and repair Computer Systems.
- Imaged and Configured PC Laptops and Desktop to companies' standard Image specifications and deployed systemthroughout North America and Canada.
- Provided Help Desk Support via phone or email at local Data Center for corporate headquarters and field locations in both North American and Canada.

Education

Bachelor of Science , Computer Engineering Technology December 2009 The University of Houston, College of Technology $i\frac{1}{4}$ City , State Computer Engineering Technology

Computer networks, Communications Circuits, Telecommunications, Data communication, Embedded systems, Microprocessors architecture, C/C++ Programming, Unix Operating System, Comptia A+, Comptia Network+

Professional Affiliations

Member, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) 2008-Present Member, Technology Society (Cy-Fair College) 2004-2006 University of Houston - College of Technology Alumni 2010-Present

Skills

A+, Active Directory, AD, Apple, AS/400, C, C++ Programming, cisco, Citrix, Hardware, Computer networks, Client, clients, customer service, Dell, dependable, email, Embedded systems, hard drive, Help Desk Support, HP, Image, Laptops, management skills, Microprocessors, access, Microsoft Office Suite, office, SharePoint, Win, 2000, 9x, MS Windows NT, motherboard, multitasking, Network, NIC cards, Norton Ghost, OS, problem solving, PXE, Quality Control, self-motivated, Servers, SLA, team player, Desktop support, Telecommunications, telephony, phones, phone, troubleshoot, Unix Operating System, VERITAS, video, VOIP